

### **Martin Maca** Junior Software Developer

### Contact details

**\( +420 601 531 920** 

remote, willing to relocate

# Core Skills

- Programming
- CAD design
- Design of single-purpose machines
- Project planing
- Scheaduling

# **Professional Profile**

With 8 years of diverse experience in industrial automation, I have specialized in areas such as machine design, programming machine logic, HMI systems design and programming, as well as servicing industrial robots and machines. I have a good proficiency in a range of CAD software, high level of proficiency in programming Epson industrial robots, I also have experience programming PLCs in Structured Text, a standardized IEC 61131-3 language. I am passionate about software development, with varied experience in programming languages such as C++, Java, HTML, and Processing.

# **Career Summary**

Feb 2023 - Present Internac Solutions, s.r.o., Kuřim Czech Republic

Research and Development Specialist

Outline

Internac Solutions is a non-profit organization focused on helping SMEs within our region with automation and digitalization. My primary role in the company is to integrate and program different automation systems and try to find new and innovative ways to use available hardware and software.

2017 - 2022 Opticontrol s.r.o., Lelekovice Czech Republic

Programmer and design Engineer

Outline

Opticontrol is a company focused on industrial automation. Main area of focus is single machine design and manufacturing, mainly for the automotive industry. I was tasked with designing and programming of the single purpose machines, and I got to experience the complete lifecycle of each machine.

2016 - 2017 Balak Stroje Tišnov s.r.o., Tišnov

Machine technician

Outline

Small family company focused on designing and building machining tools. Their main customers are companies in the automotive industry.

Jan 2015 - Dec 2015 Global Languages, Pereira, Colombia

Engligh teacher

Outline

Teaching English to kids and adults as part of a AIESEC student intership program.

### **Education**

- Bachelor degree | Brno University of Technology | 2011 2014
   Student Exchange Program | Bountiful High School, Utah, USA | Jan 2008 Jul 2008

### Certificates

- Universal Robots Advanced training | Prague, Czech Republic 2023
- Epson Robots Maintenance | Meerbush, Germany 2019
  National Welding Certificate MAG 135 1.1 | Brno, Czech Republic 2016